<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity>
  <Identity>
    <History>
Gorgo of Sparta was one of the best-known women of the Persian War generation and a rare Greek woman named by Herodotus. She was the daughter and only known child of King Cleomenes I of the Agiad house, and later the wife of King Leonidas I. Herodotus presents her as politically perceptive even as a child: when Aristagoras of Miletus tried to bribe Cleomenes into supporting the Ionian Revolt, Gorgo warned her father that the foreigner would corrupt him if he did not leave. Years later, she was credited with solving another crisis. The exiled Spartan king Demaratus sent Sparta a secret warning of Xerxes' invasion, hidden beneath wax on a writing tablet; Gorgo advised scraping away the wax, revealing the message.

Spartan women such as Gorgo were ultimately expected to produce strong Spartan offspring, and to that end, partook in a physical-education curriculum similar to their male peers. As part of this curriculum, Gorgo would have learned sports such as running, discus and javelin throwing, and wrestling. Gorgo would not only have been taught these sports, but also competed against her peers in various contests. The belief was that if both parents were physically strong, their child would be, as well.

In addition to her physical education, Gorgo would have been educated in academic matters. As an elite woman, she would have been taught how to read and write and would have received an education in the arts, including music, dance, and poetry. The academic curriculum of Spartan women was notably at least equivalent, if not superior, to that of Spartan males. Because of this physical and mental training, Plutarch attributes an anecdote to Gorgo in which a foreign woman notes, “You Spartan women are the only ones who rule their men.” To which Gorgo replies, “Yes, we are the only ones who give birth to men.”

She and Leonidas had a son, Pleistarchus, who succeeded after Leonidas died at Thermopylae in 480 BC, though regents governed while he was young. Later anecdotes, especially in Plutarch, portray Gorgo as the model of laconic wit and Spartan motherhood. Some sayings are hard to verify, but her remembered image is clear: intelligent, austere, patriotic, and deeply tied to Spartan royal legitimacy, discipline, household authority, dynastic continuity, and resistance to Persia in Greek memory and later enduring tradition.</History>
  </Identity>
</Entity>
