<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_unit_champion_infantry_hoplite">
  <Identity>
    <Civ>spart</Civ>
	<Lang>greek</Lang>
	<SpecificName>Skiritai Runner</SpecificName>
    <History>The Skiritai were a people who inhabited a small mountainous region in northern Laconia (the southernmost region of the Peloponnese) called Skiritis, which was subject of Sparta. They lived a rural life, dwelling in small villages and working as peasants. The Skiritai were treated similarly to the Perioikoi (second-class citizens of Sparta), being free and having the right to own land and slaves. When it came to military service, they enjoyed a high level of respect and trust from the Spartans.
	
In times of war, the Skiritai formed a 600-man elite militia corps in the Spartan army. However, they did not blend into the Spartan formation and always fought separately, just as allies would.The equipment and role of the Skiritai in battle are still unclear to this day. Sources mentioning them are scarce, but we know that the Spartans highly valued their skill and bravery and tasked them with important and risky roles. Some sources report them acting as scouting troops, advancing ahead of the main army, and guarding the army camp at night. In battle, the Skiritai are said to traditionally defend the left wing of the Spartan phalanx formation, a very important strategic position.

Because Arcadians were renowned for fighting as lightly equipped hoplites, and the Skiritai were ethnically Arcadians and saw themselves as such, it is probable they also fought as light infantry units. They may have been equipped as hoplites with a round shield, a spear, and a short sword, without any armor. Maybe they were also carrying some javelins and fought similarly to peltasts, who could engage in both melee and ranged combat.</History>
    <Icon>units/spart/champion_infantry_commando.png</Icon>
  </Identity>
  <UnitMotion>
    <WalkSpeed op="mul">1.4</WalkSpeed>
  </UnitMotion>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>units/spartans/infantry_spearman_c_runner.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
