<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_unit_hero_cavalry_spearman">
  <Health>
    <Max op="mul">3.0</Max>
  </Health>
  <Identity>
    <Civ>spart</Civ>
    <Lang>greek</Lang>
    <SpecificName>King Cleomenes III</SpecificName>
    <Classes datatype="tokens">Cleomenes</Classes>
    <History>Cleomenes III, King of Sparta in the 3rd century BC, is known for his attempts to reform the Spartan state and bring it back to its former power and glory. However, not everyone in Sparta was in favor of his actions. Cleomenes assassinated the other Spartan king and replaced him with his brother, abolished the Ephorate, and eliminated other political opponents, sort of becoming the military dictator of Sparta.

He granted full Spartan citizenship to many Perioikoi (the second highest social class) and mercenaries who had served in the Spartan forces. This brought the previously declining number of male Spartan citizens (Spartiates), the professional elite soldiers of the Spartan army, back up to 4000. He also reintroduced the traditional training system for the young and tried to restore the military-minded Spartan society. Most importantly, Cleomenes' soldiers were trained and equipped as phalangites after the Macedonian model rather than traditional Spartan hoplites. They were characterized by the use of the long pike (sarissa) instead of the typical hoplite's short spear, the smaller shield, and the tight Macedonian phalanx formation.

In 229/228 BC, Cleomenes declared war on the Achaean League, winning several battles and almost reconquering the Peloponnese. He occupied and got the support of strategically important cities, bringing the Achaean League to the brink of defeat.However, the Macedonians, under Antigonus III Doson, entered the war on the Achaean side. In the deciding Battle of Sellasia, the Spartans suffered huge losses and were decisively defeated, bringing an end to Cleomenes' campaign.</History>
    <Tooltip>Traits: Fast Speed, Heavy Charge, Trample.
Strong Against: Ranged Infantry (2x), Siege Weapons (2x).
Weak Against: Pike Infantry, Spear Infantry, Elephants, Camels.
Has 3x health of other infantry heroes. Basically an extremely tough Pikeman.</Tooltip>
    <Icon>units/spart/hero_cleomenes.png</Icon>
  </Identity>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>units/spartans/hero_cavalry_spearman_cleomenes_III_m.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
