<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_unit_hero_cavalry_swordsman">
  <Auras datatype="tokens">chin_hero_han_xin</Auras>
  <Identity>
    <Civ>chin</Civ>
    <SpecificName>Han Xin</SpecificName>
    <History>
    Han Xin was an able military general, recommended several times by Xiao He, a close advisor to Liu Bang, who finally served next to and under the much older Liu Bang, and is renowned as one of the Three Heroes of the early Han Dynasty due to conquering almost all of Liu's opponents. Many Chinese idioms originated from his specific warfare strategies. Thanks to Han Xin's brilliant flanking manuevers against Zhang Han, Han forces emerged victorious over the Three Qins in late BC 206. His 'attack from 10 sides' guerilla-like tactics during the decisive battle against the Chu general Xiang Yu, one of the most capable military leaders of the time, in BC 202 lead to the piecemeal and finally encirclement of the numerous Chu forces and to the Fall of Western Chu, unifying China for the second time. The careful Han Xin, though aware of being more and more mistrusted by Liu, who replaced all his kings, including Han Xin, by his own relatives over time, was finally accused of high treason due to the danger that emerged from his military genious and executed by being hung in a bell and being pierced by bamboo swords by Liu Bang's Empress and supposedly Xiao He in absence of Liu Bang. In an earlier trial Han Xin noted 'It is true when people say: The hunting dog becomes food as well after it is used to hunt game; a good bow is discarded when there are no birds left for shooting; an advisor dies after he helps his lord conquer a rival kingdom. Now that the empire is in place, I no longer serve any purpose!'. His last words - supposedly aged 31 - are supposed to be 'I regret not listening to Kuai Tong`s advice'. His wife and parents, and all of his clan were wiped out too by the anxious Liu Clan, supposedly preventing an early collapse of the Han Dynasty in a time when rebellions became more frequent. Han Xin's military legacy partly survived in the strategon.
	</History>
    <Icon>units/chin_hero_han_xin.png</Icon>
  </Identity>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>units/chinese/hero_han_xin.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
